so first let's talk about performance
usually when we say performance within
processor speed but even then there are
really two aspects of performance that
are not necessarily identical one is
latency it's about how long does it take
from when we start something until it's
done
the other is throughput which is how
many things can we do per second and one
would think the throughput is really 1
over latency so for example if it takes
half a second to do something then the
number of those things we can do per
second is gonna be 1 over 1/2 and we get
2 for throughput but this is not always
so think about a car assembly line we
start with just a chassis we then move
the car to where its engine is gonna be
installed we then move the car to where
some wheels are gonna be added to it
we then have some doors installed and
some hood put together and so on and now
we have a car so the latency is from
here to here here's where we began the
car here's where we have a final car but
we have an assembly line so when the
chassis moves here for the engine to be
installed the next chassis gets put
together when we have installed the
engine we move the car to the install
wheel station meanwhile the next car is
getting its engine installed and so on
so let's say that the latency is 4 hours
but it it takes something like 20 steps
for a car if each of these steps takes
the same amount of time and the cars are
just moving through these steps then our
throughput is actually 5 cars per hour
not 0.25 cars per hour so as you can see
the throughput and the latency need not
be like this